play high
높이 놀다
move
이동하다
good
좋은
OK
좋아요
You two are indeed here
너희 둘이 정말 여기 있구나
Jiaping
자핑
You've been eyeing Zuo Shuangtao for a long time, right?
오랫동안 Zuo Shuangtao를 눈여겨보셨죠?
If someone hadn't told me
누군가 나에게 말하지 않았다면
I do not know yet
나는 아직 모른다
Mr. Sir
선생님
stop fighting
싸우지 마
go away
저리 가요
open
열려 있는
stop fighting
싸우지 마
Get out of the way
비켜가세요
Section Chief Chen Section Chief Chen
첸 과장 첸 과장
go away
저리 가요
Get rid of the gas, get rid of the gas
가스 빼세요, 가스 빼세요
Step aside
비켜서 다
Where else have you been?
또 어디에 있었나요?
Section Chief Chen
첸 과장
where have they been
그들은 어디에 있었나요?
Is there any need to say that?
굳이 그런 말을 할 필요가 있나요?
Hotel
호텔
two knives
두 개의 칼
Don't talk nonsense
말도 안되는 소리 하지 마세요
We are both innocent
우리 둘 다 무죄야
If you are innocent
당신이 결백하다면
Then Captain Zhao and
그러자 자오 선장과
Are you okay bro?
괜찮아 형?
So careless
너무 부주의하다
What's this
이게 뭐야?
do not move
이동하지 않습니다
you give me
당신은 나에게
Give me
나에게주세요
do not move
이동하지 않습니다
explain
설명하다
What is written here
여기에 쓰여진 내용
Say what is this?
이게 뭐야?
elder brother
형
Is it a secret message?
비밀 메시지인가요?
have a look
보세요
you give me
당신은 나에게
do not move
이동하지 않습니다
double peach
더블 복숭아
my sweetheart
내 연인
elder brother
형
I'll come, I'll come
나는 올 것이다, 나는 올 것이다
How are you
어떻게 지내세요
Farewell for many days
여러날의 이별
Miss you endlessly
끝없이 보고 싶어
I asked several times before asking
물어보기 전에 몇 번이나 물어봤지
It turns out you went to Shanghai
알고보니 상하이에 갔었구나
You left Wuhan
당신은 우한을 떠났습니다
Didn't even say a word to me
나한테는 한마디도 안했는데
I think you have really changed your mind
정말 마음이 변하신 것 같아요
In fact, over the past half year or so
실제로 지난 반년 정도 동안
I have noticed
나는 눈치 챘다
You are really becoming less and less interested in me
너 정말 나한테 관심이 점점 줄어들고 있어
But I still didn't think of it
그런데 아직은 생각 못 했네요
You will be so heartless
넌 정말 무정할 거야
in recent days
최근 며칠 동안
I'm tossing and turning
뒤척이고 돌리고 있어요
It’s hard to let go
??? 놔두기 힘들어
I always think of the time we spent together
우리가 함께 보낸 시간을 늘 생각해요
us at that time
그때의 우리
Qingqing Zipei
칭칭 지페이
I'm thinking
나는 생각 중입니다
Not seen for a day
하루 동안 보이지 않음
Like March
3월처럼
Mountains are high and rivers are long
산은 높고 강은 길다
I miss you so much
너무 보고 싶어요
hold an umbrella
우산을 들고
make a pot of tea
차 한 주전자를 만들다
Counting the time with you
너와의 시간을 헤아려
I really want to be like that
나는 정말로 그렇게 되고 싶다
Tenchojiku
텐초지쿠
Did you write it?
당신이 썼나요?
I didn't write this
나는 이것을 쓰지 않았다
Not written by you
당신이 쓴 게 아니야
Gao Fang said he didn’t write it
Gao Fang은 자신이 쓴 적이 없다고 말했습니다.
Then who wrote this?
그럼 이 글은 누가 썼나요?
Who wrote it
누가 썼니
Remember?
기억하다?
repeat
반복하다
After meeting Gao Fang at Qinka Cafe
Qinka Cafe에서 Gao Fang을 만난 후
Confirm the secret message in hand first
먼저 손에 든 비밀 메시지를 확인하세요.
Then wait for an opportunity to poison the coffee
그런 다음 커피에 독을 넣을 기회를 기다리십시오.
finally, I understand
드디어 이해가 되네요
Guoguo assassinates Yamashita
궈궈가 야마시타를 암살하다
It's to get back a secret letter
비밀편지를 돌려받기 위해서야
But then I don’t know why the secret message was lost again
그런데 왜 또 비밀글이 없어졌는지 모르겠네요
She once suspected that the secret message had been taken away by me.
그녀는 한때 내가 비밀 메시지를 가져갔다고 의심했습니다.
It turns out that the secret letter is in Gao Fang's hands
비밀 편지가 Gao Fang의 손에 있음이 밝혀졌습니다.
And used this to force Guoguo to date him
그리고 이를 이용해 궈궈에게 데이트를 강요했습니다.
Now the military commander wants to take action against Gao
이제 군 사령관은 Gao에 대한 조치를 취하고 싶어합니다.
But Guoguo definitely doesn’t know
하지만 Guoguo는 확실히 모르나요?
Zhang Shuyun saw her meeting with Gao Fang
Zhang Shuyun은 Gao Fang과의 만남을 보았습니다.
And Zhang Shuyun will definitely inform Zhao An of this matter.
그리고 Zhang Shuyun은 이 문제를 Zhao An에게 확실히 알릴 것입니다.
So the actions of military commanders
그래서 군 지휘관의 행동
It's possible that they are all under Zhao An's surveillance
모두 조안의 감시를 받고 있을 가능성이 있다
Na Guoguo’s identity
나궈궈의 정체
It's completely exposed
완전히 노출됐네요
You two are indeed here
너희 둘이 정말 여기 있구나
Jiaping
자핑
You've been eyeing Zuo Shuangtao for a long time, right?
오랫동안 Zuo Shuangtao를 눈여겨보셨죠?
If someone hadn't told me
누군가 나에게 말하지 않았다면
I do not know yet
나는 아직 모른다
You two are too brave.
너희 둘은 너무 용감하다.
Jiaping
자핑
he and I
그와 나
We met in Wuhan
우한에서 만났어요
what relationship
어떤 관계
What's their relationship?
그들의 관계는 무엇입니까?
Isn't this obvious?
이것은 명백하지 않습니까?
really
정말
Been together for a while
한동안 함께 있었어
I didn’t expect it, Zuo Shuangtao
예상 못했어요, Zuo Shuangtao
Two boats
보트 두 척
Who knows if there are only two boats?
보트가 두 대뿐인지 누가 알겠습니까?
Get out of here
여기서 나가
Jiaping
자핑
We only have a short period of time
우리에겐 시간이 짧다
It's very short
매우 짧습니다
You will be with him forever
당신은 그 사람과 영원히 함께 할 것입니다
We're going to spend a lifetime together
우리는 평생을 함께 보낼 거예요
you tell me a short time
잠깐만 말해봐
He is the kind of person who is sour.
그는 신맛이 나는 사람입니다.
It's just talk
그냥 얘기예요
I didn't take it seriously at all
나는 전혀 심각하게 생각하지 않았다
you didn't take it seriously
넌 그걸 심각하게 받아들이지 않았어
Why did you leave this letter?
왜 이 편지를 남겼나요?
I just received it
방금 받았어요
Originally I wanted to get rid of it
원래는 없애고 싶었는데
But then I couldn't find it
그런데 그때는 못 찾았어요
I thought it was lost
잃어버린 줄 알았는데
You thought you lost it
당신은 그것을 잃어버린 줄 알았는데
Did you receive this letter?
이 편지를 받았나요?
You must have lost your soul with excitement.
설렘으로 영혼을 잃었나 봐요.
So what do you want from me?
그럼 나한테 원하는 게 뭐야?
During that time, war was raging
그 동안 전쟁이 격렬했고
We are separated again
우리는 또 헤어졌다
a letter i wrote to you
내가 당신에게 쓴 편지
two months
이 개월
I didn't receive a reply for two months
두 달 동안 답장을 받지 못했어요
I don't even dare to think about it
감히 생각조차 할 수 없어
Can we still be together?
우리 계속 함께 있을 수 있을까?
Can you survive tomorrow?
내일은 살아남을 수 있을까?
I don't even know
나도 모르겠어
We are all degraded people
우리는 모두 타락한 사람들이다
That is
그건
Have a better time
더 좋은 시간 보내세요
What's wrong
뭐가 문제 야
You are still reasonable
당신은 여전히 ​​합리적이다
How dare you hit me
감히 나를 때리다니
roll
롤
I never want to see you again
난 다시는 당신을 보고 싶지 않아요
What are you looking at?
무엇을 보고 있나요?
Never seen it
본 적 없음
letter
편지
How could it be on you
어떻게 그게 너한테 있을 수 있니?
I
나
Did you steal it from Zuo Shuangtao?
Zuo Shuangtao에게서 훔쳤습니까?
say
말하다
to be honest
솔직히 말하자면
yes
예
I got it from her
나는 그녀에게서 그것을 얻었다
I always
난 항상
Secretly in love with Miss Zuo
Miss Zuo와 비밀리에 사랑에 빠졌습니다.
So that day she came to work at the commercial bank
그래서 그날 그녀는 상업은행에 일하러 왔어요
When I helped her move things
내가 그녀의 물건 옮기는 것을 도와줬을 때
took it from her pocket
그녀의 주머니에서 그것을 꺼냈다
So you use this letter
그래서 당신은 이 편지를 사용합니다
Threaten my wife
내 아내를 위협해
Date with you
당신과 데이트
Is it right
맞아
right
오른쪽
good
좋은
I'll ask you one last time
마지막으로 하나만 묻겠습니다
Have you done anything else with my wife?
내 아내와 다른 일을 한 적 있나요?
I don't
나는 아니에요
I I'm really just with her
난 정말 그 사람이랑 같이 있는 거야
Come out and talk
나와서 얘기해
I really didn't do anything else
나 진짜 다른 건 아무것도 안 했는데
Okay, Jiaping
알았어, 자핑
calm down
진정하다
Walk
걷다
Captain Zhao
자오 선장
Why are you here?
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
passing by
에 의해 전달
Want to come in and have a cup of coffee
들어와서 커피한잔 하고싶다
Something happened to you
당신에게 무슨 일이 일어났어요
OK
좋아요
You can go
당신은 갈 수 있습니다
Drink coffee
커피를 마시다
Can you drink high and put a letter in your pocket?
술을 많이 마시고 주머니에 편지를 넣을 수 있습니까?
two knives
두 개의 칼
Is this interesting
이게 흥미롭나요?
Gao Fang and Zuo Shuangtao just have a cup of coffee
Gao Fang과 Zuo Shuangtao는 커피 한 잔을 마시고 있습니다.
What does it have to do with you
그게 당신과 무슨 관련이 있나요?
You must help Section Chief Chen find out the truth
당신은 첸 과장이 진실을 알 수 있도록 도와야 합니다
What other love letters should I find?
또 어떤 러브레터를 찾아야 할까요?
token of love
사랑의 증표
Let me turn it over
뒤집어 볼까
Have you turned it over?
뒤집어 보셨나요?
You made Section Chief Chen
첸 과장을 만드셨어요
The misunderstanding between Zuo Shuangtao and the others deepened
Zuo Shuangtao와 다른 사람들 사이의 오해는 깊어졌습니다.
Don't you want to demolish your home?
집을 철거하고 싶지 않으세요?
No
아니요
How to explain
설명하는 방법
How can I explain
어떻게 설명할 수 있나요?
Explain it
설명 해봐
roll
롤
Acting is too tiring
연기는 너무 피곤해
Fortunately, the tacit understanding is good
다행히 암묵적인 이해는 좋다
Is this what you want?
이것이 당신이 원하는 것입니까?
Don't you ask me what this is?
이게 뭔지 나한테 묻지 마?
If you want to tell me
나에게 말하고 싶다면
It's not like he was coerced by Gao Fang, right?
Gao Fang에게 강요당한 것은 아니죠?
At least there will be speculation.
적어도 추측은 있을 것이다.
I don't want to guess
추측하고 싶지 않아요
I am
그래요
dawdle
꾸물거리다
Eat together
같이 먹자
Where are these secrets of yours?
당신의 비밀은 어디에 있습니까?
I don't want to know either
나도 알고 싶지 않아
Not interested either
관심도 없음
Moreover
게다가
know your secret
너의 비밀을 알아라
Doesn't do me any good either
나에게도 아무 소용이 없어
Then how do you know
그럼 어떻게 알아?
Gao Fang used this to coerce me
Gao Fang은 이것을 이용하여 나를 강압했습니다.
When you and Gao Zang met at Mega Park,
당신과 Gao Zang이 메가파크에서 만났을 때,
Zhang Shuyun saw it
장수윤이 봤어
Then it reached Lu Fangfang’s ears
그러다가 Lu Fangfang의 귀에 도달했습니다.
What a careless
정말 부주의하다
did not expect
기대하지 않았다
In the end, it was a woman’s long tongue that helped me
결국 나를 도와준 건 여자의 긴 혀였다.
no matter what
무슨 일이 있어도
Thank you
감사합니다
Why are you thanking me?
왜 나한테 고마워해요?
I still have to say sorry to you.
아직도 미안하다고 말해야 해요.
I deducted one for you
내가 당신을 위해 하나를 공제했습니다
Unfounded bad reputation
근거 없는 나쁜 평판
And slapped you
그리고 당신을 때렸어요
It's no big deal, right?
별거 아니죠?
I have nothing
나는 아무것도 없다
It's for you
그것은 당신을 위해
Cuckolded
오만한
Plus two knives
게다가 칼도 2개
Adding fuel to the fire
불에 연료 추가하기
Enough to be laughed at for a while
한동안 웃어넘길 만큼
yes
예
And from now on
그리고 지금부터
Luo Guanqun and I have more common topics.
Luo Guanqun과 저는 더 공통된 주제를 가지고 있습니다.
You come to Shanghai
상하이에 오셨군요
Just for this
단지 이것을 위해서
So now you've got it
이제 당신은 그것을 얻었습니다
I will go
나는 갈 것이다
do you think
당신은 생각합니까
I used you
나는 당신을 이용했다
No
아니요
look
바라보다
the two of us
우리 둘
Help each other solve their own troubles
서로의 문제를 해결하도록 도와주세요
Isn't this good?
이거 좋지 않아?
Just now I was thinking here
지금 막 여기서 생각하고 있었어
I just understand
나는 단지 이해한다
It turns out you took every detail into consideration
당신은 모든 세부 사항을 고려한 것으로 나타났습니다
If it hadn't been for that slap in the face
그 뺨을 때리는 일만 없었더라면
There is no way I can leave so simply.
그렇게 간단히 떠날 수 있는 방법은 없습니다.
If you were an agent
당신이 대리인이었다면
It must be the top
상위권이어야 합니다
Stop it
그만해요
What kind of agent am I?
나는 어떤 대리인인가?
At best, I'm just a beaten thief.
기껏해야 나는 그저 구타당한 도둑일 뿐이다.
Right
오른쪽
I have a longer memory
기억력이 더 길어요
Why are you hanging out with traitors?
왜 반역자와 어울리나요?
Think about it
생각해 보세요
On the beach in Shanghai
상하이 해변에서
right
오른쪽
Let's eat together
같이 먹자
But I think
하지만 나는 생각해
You also have something like this
너도 이런거 있잖아
what
무엇
Secret
비밀
have a secret from me
나한테 비밀이 하나 있어
But I'm also worried about you
하지만 나도 네가 걱정돼
We just got married not long ago
우리 결혼한지 얼마 안됐는데
I just left
방금 나갔어
Will they doubt you again?
그들이 당신을 다시 의심할까요?
Won't
습관
Think about it
생각해 보세요
You gave me a big green hat
당신은 나에게 큰 녹색 모자를 줬어요
I slapped you
나는 당신을 때렸다
It's like this
이렇습니다
We parted ways
우리는 헤어졌다
Isn't that normal?
그게 정상이 아닌가요?
He won't doubt it
그는 그것을 의심하지 않을 것이다
This is the result you want
이것이 당신이 원하는 결과입니다
Yeah
응
Now
지금
For both of us
우리 모두에게
this
이것
These are the best results, right?
이게 최고의 결과죠?
right
오른쪽
Just a play
그냥 연극
only
오직
Our acting skills are so good
우리 연기력 너무 좋아
Acting well
연기 잘함
I almost believed it
나는 거의 그것을 믿었다.
And you
당신은요
Do you feel this way?
이런 느낌이 드나요?
I feel like I almost believed it
거의 믿었던 것 같아
If this were a movie
이게 영화였다면
I hope it can go on forever
영원히 계속될 수 있기를 바랍니다
goodbye
안녕히 가세요
Why didn't you kill Gao Fang?
왜 Gao Fang을 죽이지 않았습니까?
many things
많은 것들
It can't be solved by killing people
사람을 죽여도 해결이 안 된다.
how did you do that
당신은 그렇게 않았다 방법
I have my way
난 내 방식대로 해
He returned the secret message to me
그 사람이 나한테 비밀편지를 돌려줬어
Back to you
당신에게 돌아
Why didn't I see it?
왜 나는 그것을 보지 못했습니까?
Maybe you didn't care
어쩌면 넌 신경쓰지 않았을지도 몰라
How did you convince him?
그를 어떻게 설득했나요?
Women have women's ways
여자에겐 여자만의 방식이 있다
Especially when facing a
특히 직면할 때
When you like your own person
자신의 사람이 마음에 들 때
But I clearly saw it
하지만 난 분명히 봤어
You poisoned the coffee?
커피에 독을 넣었나요?
I replaced the poison with water
독약을 물로 바꿨어요
If Gao Fang is not dead
Gao Fang이 죽지 않았다면
You will take action
조치를 취하게 됩니다
But in that case
하지만 그런 경우에는
There's no way I can tell you I got it
내가 그것을 얻었다고 말할 수 있는 방법은 없어요
You are good at making opinions again
또 의견을 잘 내시네요
Zhao An has been monitoring me and Gao Fang
Zhao An은 나와 Gao Fang을 모니터링하고 있습니다.
If I hadn't made the decision
내가 결정을 내리지 않았다면
We can still stand here and talk
우리는 여전히 여기 서서 이야기할 수 있어요
I hope you have merit
당신에게 장점이 있기를 바랍니다
I don't care about you
난 너한테 관심 없어
Get on board first
먼저 탑승하세요
Let’s talk about it after leaving Shanghai
상하이를 떠나서 얘기하자
where to
어디로
To Jiaxing
가흥으로
There is a traffic line over there
저기에 교통선이 있어
Then find a way to get to Chongqing
그런 다음 충칭으로 가는 방법을 찾아보세요.
Let's go
갑시다
You said that thing
그런 말을 했었잖아
I'll help you keep an eye on it
지켜볼 수 있게 도와드릴게요
Contact you if found
발견되면 연락주세요
good
좋은
okay
좋아요
Then walk slowly and don’t miss the two bosses.
그럼 천천히 걸으면서 두 보스를 놓치지 마세요.
Don't give it away
버리지 마세요
Good words
좋은 말
Looks like you're in a good mood today
오늘 기분이 좋은 것 같군요
old road
오래된 길
This is a secret message from the military commander
이것은 군 사령관의 비밀 메시지입니다.
Gao Fang has translated part of it
Gao Fang이 일부를 번역했습니다.
The remaining part
남은 부분
Please organize and arrange experts to continue deciphering
계속해서 해독할 수 있도록 전문가를 구성하고 배치해 주십시오.
Since this secret letter
이 비밀편지 이후로
So important for military unification
군사통일에 매우 중요
There must be some confidential information here
여기에는 기밀 정보가 있어야 합니다.
There are still old roads
아직 오래된 도로가 남아있어요
Zuo Shuangtao
주오솽타오
Already evacuated
이미 대피함
Crisis resolved
위기가 해결됨
Can I apply?
신청할 수 있나요?
Keep lurking
계속 숨어있어
But still can't let down our guard
하지만 여전히 우리의 경계심을 늦출 수는 없습니다
How is the secret peace talks going?
비밀 평화회담은 어떻게 진행되고 있나요?
Two Japanese representatives
일본 대표 2명
No clues yet
아직 단서가 없습니다
But there is new progress
하지만 새로운 진전이 있어
I'm still tracing
아직 추적 중이에요
According to some intelligence analysis
일부 정보 분석에 따르면
Chiang Kai-shek is likely to be involved in this peace negotiation
이번 평화협상에는 장개석이 참여할 가능성이 높다.
Abandon the policy of resisting Japan and tolerating communism
항일과 공산주의를 용인하는 정책을 포기하라
Even recognized the so-called Manchukuo
소위 만주국도 인정했다
This is not a peace talk
이건 평화회담이 아니다
This is clearly betraying the country.
이는 명백히 국가를 배반하는 행위이다.
But if there is no hard evidence
하지만 확실한 증거가 없다면
Chongqing will never admit it
충칭은 절대 인정하지 않을 것이다
so your task
그러니 당신의 임무
extremely important
매우 중요한
clear
분명한
Prepare today
오늘 준비하세요
What are you taking with you?
당신은 무엇을 가지고 가고 있습니까?
You can take anything
뭐든지 가져가도 돼
this is not OK
이건 안 돼
This is a flower-and-bird pattern brush carved from bamboo during the Wanli period of the Ming Dynasty.
명나라 만리시대에 대나무를 깎아 만든 화조문의 붓이다.
It’s my treasure
그거??? 내 보물이야
you
너
Absolutely not
절대적으로하지
Tell me about you
너에 대해 말해줘
Married only a few days
결혼한지 며칠 안됐는데
How come it's like this?
어쩌다 이렇게 된 걸까요?
This cuckold is on my head
이 오쟁이 진 남편이 내 머리에있다.
If it were you, you could bear it
너였다면 참을 수 있었을 텐데
Take the overall situation into consideration
전반적인 상황을 고려하여
How can I take care of the overall situation?
전체적인 상황을 어떻게 처리할 수 있나요?
How can I take care of the overall situation, Lao Luo?
라오루오 씨, 전반적인 상황을 어떻게 처리할 수 있나요?
Just one day
단 하루 만
The news spread throughout all the trading houses.
이 소식은 모든 무역회사에 퍼졌습니다.
when i came in
내가 들어왔을 때
The way everyone looks at me is wrong
다들 나를 보는 시선이 틀려
It's like my face is covered
얼굴이 가려진거같아
Everything has turned green for me
내겐 모든 것이 녹색으로 변했어요
My face is green now, right?
내 얼굴이 지금 초록색이 된 거죠?
OK OK OK
오케이 오케이 오케이
Not green
녹색이 아님
No one is green
초록색 사람은 아무도 없어
Men should be a little open-minded
남자들은 좀 개방적이어야 해
Otherwise, how could it be such a big deal?
그렇지 않다면 어떻게 그렇게 큰 일이 될 수 있겠습니까?
I didn't mean it to be a big deal
큰일을 하려는 건 아니었는데
As long as you can achieve great things
위대한 일을 성취할 수 있는 한
I'll hang out with you
나는 당신과 어울릴 것이다
Just have something to eat.
그냥 먹을 것 좀 드세요.
you say you
당신은 당신을 말한다
Where is Miss Zuo?
Miss Zuo는 어디에 있나요?
Ran
란
Then why don't you go look for it?
그럼 가서 찾아보는 게 어때?
How can I find it?
어떻게 찾을 수 있나요?
I slapped her
나는 그녀를 때렸다
I can get her temper back
나는 그 사람의 화를 되돌릴 수 있어요
What a pity about my vegetable oil business
내 식물성 기름 사업이 참 안타깝네요.
Not what do you mean?
아니 무슨 말이에요?
Your business is business
당신의 사업은 사업이다
Your brother’s face is not a face
오빠 얼굴은 얼굴이 아니야
OK OK OK
오케이 오케이 오케이
You are totally unreliable
당신은 완전히 신뢰할 수 없습니다
What do you mean I'm unreliable?
내가 신뢰할 수 없다는 게 무슨 말이에요?
When I was the most uncomfortable and wronged
내가 가장 불편하고 억울했을 때
If you don't comfort me, forget it
나를 위로하지 않으면 잊어버려
Are you adding insult to injury?
부상에 모욕을 더하고 있습니까?
are you my brother
당신은 내 형제입니까?
I treat you as a brother
나는 당신을 형제처럼 대합니다.
Do you consider me a brother?
나를 형제라고 생각하시나요?
You told me last time you liked this stuff
저번에 이 물건이 마음에 든다고 말했잖아
I tried my best to find it for you
나는 당신을 위해 그것을 찾으려고 최선을 다했습니다
What do I do if I find you?
당신을 찾으면 어떻게 해야 하나요?
I'm done with pouting.
삐죽거리는 소리는 이제 끝났습니다.
By distinction
구별하여
This is baby
이건 자기야
Get off
하차
By distinction
구별하여
This is baby, this is baby
이건 자기야, 이건 자기야
You let go, let go
넌 놔, 놔
I was joking just now
나 지금 농담하고 있었어
I apologize
사과한다
loosen loosen loosen loosen
풀다 풀다 풀다 풀다
What I just said were all angry words
내가 방금 한 말은 다 화난 말들이었어
You are unreliable
당신은 신뢰할 수 없습니다
Who can be trusted?
누가 믿을 수 있나요?
Where did you get this?
이거 어디서 났어?
You don’t care where I got it from
내가 그걸 어디서 얻었는지 넌 상관 안 해
I tell you
나는 당신에게 말한다
If you're to blame for this, blame Zhao An
만약 당신이 이것을 비난하려면 조안(Zhao An)을 비난하라
He is everywhere
그는 어디에나 있다
What’s the latest news about Feng Qi?
Feng Qi에 대한 최신 뉴스는 무엇입니까?
This guy has been disappearing all day long
이 사람이 하루종일 사라졌어요
There must be some secret mission
뭔가 비밀 임무가 있는 게 틀림없어
do you have any news
무슨 소식 있어?
When I went to the military police headquarters for a meeting
헌병본부에 회의하러 갔을 때
I heard Kimura and Zhao An muttering something?
기무라와 자오안이 중얼거리는 걸 들었어요?
I only heard one person's name
한 사람 이름만 들었는데
Jiang Zhaoguo
지앙 자오궈
right
오른쪽
I have no idea
나는 전혀 모른다
Does he have anything to do with Feng Qi's recent mission?
그는 Feng Qi의 최근 임무와 관련이 있나요?
have no idea
전혀 모른다
Jiang Zhaoguo
지앙 자오궈
Sadness can be contagious to others
슬픔은 다른 사람에게도 전염될 수 있다
Happiness can also infect others
행복은 다른 사람에게도 영향을 미칠 수 있다
so
그래서
hope i'm with you
내가 너와 함께 있기를 바라
It's a little more sad
좀 더 아쉽네요
Still happier
그래도 더 행복해
play high
높이 놀다
I know you have a lot of worries
걱정이 많으신 거 알아요
But as long as we face the sunshine together
하지만 우리가 함께 햇빛을 마주하는 한
It will all pass
다 지나갈 거야
Just smile
그냥 웃어
Really ugly
정말 못생겼어
come and learn from me
와서 나한테 배워
knew
알고 있었다
Jiaping
자핑
This is Xiao Jin, the person in charge here
이곳 담당자 샤오진 입니다
This newspaper is full of these news
이 신문에는 이런 소식이 가득해요
If you have anything, just ask him
무슨 일 있으면 그 사람한테 물어보세요.
Entertainment gossip
엔터테인먼트 가십
Celebrity Scandal
연예인 스캔들
Shocking revelations
충격적인 폭로
sexy nude photos
섹시한 누드 사진
We have whatever we want here
여기에는 우리가 원하는 것이 무엇이든 있습니다
What do you want to know?
무엇을 알고 싶나요?
Does Hanlu know?
한루는 알고 있나요?
Do our job
우리 일을 해라
How could you not recognize Hanlu?
한루를 어떻게 알아보지 못하셨나요?
There is another name
또 다른 이름이 있다
My name is Jiang Zhaoguo
내 이름은 장자오궈(Jiang Zhaoguo)입니다.
Do you have an impression?
인상이 있나요?
Jiang Zhaoguo
지앙 자오궈
This name is a bit unfamiliar
이름이 좀 낯설네요
You put Jiang Zhaoguo and Han Lu
Jiang Zhaoguo와 Han Lu를 넣으세요
These two names are associated with each other
이 두 이름은 서로 연관되어 있습니다.
Jiang Zhaoguo
지앙 자오궈
cold dew
차가운 이슬
wait
기다리다
I said why is it a bit strange?
왜 조금 이상합니까?
This was news two years ago
2년전 뉴스였네요
This mysterious boyfriend
이 신비한 남자 친구
His name is Jiang Zhaoguo
이름이 장자오궈인 사람
At that time, he was an official of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Nationalist Government
당시 그는 국민정부 외무부 간부였다.
thank you
감사합니다
go ahead
어서
i know now
나는 이제 안다
Why are they looking for Hanlu?
그들은 왜 한루를 찾는 걸까요?
What's the matter with you?
당신에게 무슨 문제가 있습니까?
No eyes
눈 없음
sorry
죄송합니다
sorry Sorry
미안 미안
Sugar-coated haws
설탕으로 코팅된 산사나무
Miss
놓치다
I will contact you when there is news about the house.
집 소식이 들리면 연락드리겠습니다.
Walk slowly
천천히 걷기
good
좋은
You two, stop here
너희 둘은 여기서 멈춰라
That's right, it's you two
그렇구나, 너희 둘이구나
I said you two are
내가 말했잖아 너희 둘은
Are they husband and wife or lovers?
그들은 남편과 아내인가, 아니면 연인인가?
It’s not that you have big eyes
눈이 큰 건 아니지
for breathing
호흡을 위해
We are both men
우리 둘 다 남자예요
Since they are all men
다 남자라서
Two people make love every day
두 사람은 매일 사랑을 나눈다.
What are you doing hanging around in the French Concession?
프랑스 조계지에서 뭐하고 계시나요?
Such a wide road
이렇게 넓은 길
Are you taking too much care?
너무 신경쓰고 있는 걸까요?
Don't talk nonsense to me here
여기서 나한테 말도 안되는 소리 하지마
Don't think I don't know
내가 모른다고 생각하지 마세요
Have you two always
너희 둘은 항상 있니?
Follow that pretty lady who just came in?
방금 들어온 그 예쁜 아가씨를 따라가볼까?
There are so many people on the road
길에 사람이 너무 많아서
Why are you following her just because you said it was us?
왜 우리라고 했다는 이유로 따라오나요?
I tell you
나는 당신에게 말한다
I'm the patrolman of the French Concession
나는 프랑스 조계지의 순찰대원이에요
don't let me see it again
다시는 볼 수 없게 해줘
You are sneaking around in the French Concession
당신은 프랑스 조계지를 몰래 돌아다니고 있습니다
What should you do?
당신은 무엇을 해야 합니까?
Take a look at this set
이 세트를 살펴보세요
No. 22, Petain Road, French Concession
22, Petain Road, 프랑스 조계지
This area is a high-end residential area
이 지역은 고급 주거 지역입니다.
All the upper class people live here
여기 상류층 사람들 다 살아요
Not only is the environment beautiful
환경이 아름다울 뿐만 아니라
And ah
그리고 아
There is also a patrol house patrolling 24 hours a day.
24시간 순찰하는 순찰대도 있습니다.
Of course, the price will be slightly higher
물론 가격은 조금 더 높겠지만
Price is not an issue
가격은 문제가 아니다
but
하지만
I don't want anyone to know
누구에게도 알리고 싶지 않아
I rented a house with you
너랑 집을 빌렸어
Don't worry about this
이것에 대해 걱정하지 마십시오
We will never leak it
절대 유출하지 않겠습니다
any information about customers
고객에 관한 모든 정보
coming
오는
Miss Hanlu
미스 한루
Jiaping
자핑
why are you here
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
Can I talk to you in the car?
차에서 얘기 좀 할 수 있을까요?
What to talk about
무슨 얘기를 할까?
about a friend of yours
네 친구에 대해서
Miss Hanlu
미스 한루
You rented the house for that friend, right?
그 친구를 위해 집을 빌렸죠?
how
어떻게
you follow me
너는 나를 따라와
No
아니요
Don't get me wrong
오해하지 마세요
We are not stalking you
우리는 당신을 스토킹하는 것이 아닙니다
Instead, you followed the person who followed you.
대신 당신은 당신을 따라온 사람을 따라갔습니다.
I didn't find anyone following me
나를 팔로우하는 사람을 찾지 못했습니다.
If Miss Hanlu finds out
한루씨가 알면
Those colleagues of mine
그 동료들은
He must have been shot a long time ago
그 사람은 분명 오래 전에 총에 맞았을 거예요
so now
그래서 지금
You can talk to me
나한테 얘기해도 돼
What’s the story about your friend?
당신의 친구에 대한 이야기는 무엇입니까?
If Miss Hanlu
미스 한루라면
What you still don’t want to tell me
아직도 나한테 말하고 싶지 않은 게 뭐야?
I can reveal some information to you first
먼저 몇 가지 정보를 알려드릴 수 있습니다
The Chongqing government is working with the Japanese Prime Minister
충칭 정부는 일본 총리와 협력하고 있습니다
Planning secret peace talks
비밀 평화 회담 계획
However, the Japanese military tried their best to obstruct
그러나 일본군은 이를 막기 위해 최선을 다했다.
and bring the negotiators from both sides
그리고 양측의 협상가들을 데려오세요.
They were all listed as targets for assassination.
그들은 모두 암살 대상으로 지정되었습니다.
And the Chongqing government
그리고 충칭 정부
Deputy Director-General of the Asian Department of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs
외교부 아시아부 차관
Jiang Zhaoguo
지앙 자오궈
He is the representative of China this time
이번엔 중국 대표다
I'm just an actor
나는 그냥 배우예요
Not interested in political matters
정치적인 문제에는 관심이 없습니다
This person you are talking about
당신이 말하는 이 사람
I don't know him either
나도 그 사람을 몰라
good
좋은
But
하지만
I still have to remind Miss Hanlu
아직도 한루 선생님에게 상기시켜 줘야 해요
The people following you are Zhao An's men
당신을 따르는 사람들은 조안의 부하들입니다
So the house you rent is no longer safe
그래서 당신이 임대하는 집은 더 이상 안전하지 않습니다
Can I get off the car?
차에서 내릴 수 있나요?
certainly
틀림없이
Hello
안녕하세요
it's me
나야
Have you rented the house?
집을 빌렸나요?
I'm being followed
나는 추적당하고 있다
there are two people
두 사람이 있어요
Followed me to the rental company
나를 따라 렌탈 회사까지 갔어
What
무엇
you
너
Do you see who they are?
그들이 누구인지 아시나요?
I happened to meet a friend
우연히 친구를 만났어요
know those two people
그 두 사람을 알아요
They are the Military Police Headquarters
헌병사령부입니다
A subordinate of a secret intelligence station
비밀 정보국의 부하
You're not in danger, are you?
당신은 위험하지 않습니까?
No
아니요
But that house
그런데 그 집
You don't have to worry about the house.
집에 대해서는 걱정하지 않으셔도 됩니다.
I will figure it out myself
내가 직접 알아낼게
sorry
죄송합니다
I can't help you
나는 당신을 도울 수 없습니다
No
아니요
It was my fault
내 잘못이었어
i shouldn't
난 그러면 안 돼
Implicate you in my work
당신을 내 일에 연루시키세요
I am worried about you
난 네가 걱정돼
those people
저 사람들
Will I also find you?
나도 당신을 찾을 수 있을까요?
Do not worry
걱정 하지마
they won't find me
그들은 나를 찾지 못할 거야
Where I live is very secluded.
내가 사는 곳은 매우 외딴 곳이다.
Are you coming to Shanghai this time?
이번에 상하이에 오시나요?
What exactly is the job?
직업이 정확히 무엇인가요?
this
이것
i can't tell you
나는 당신에게 말할 수 없습니다
Very dangerous, right?
매우 위험하지 않나요?
I work
나는 일한다
Nothing is not dangerous
아무것도 위험하지 않아요
Then after you finish this work
그럼 이 일을 마치고 나면
Will you stay in Shanghai?
상하이에 남을 건가요?
Going back to Chongqing?
충칭으로 돌아가나요?
I can't even tell now
지금은 말할 수도 없어요
It depends on the results of my work this time
이번 작업의 결과에 따라 달라집니다
So this time
그래서 이번에는
There's no end to the meeting again
또 회의는 끝이 없어
two days later
이틀 후
It's still this time
아직 이 시간이야
I will contact you again
다시 연락드리겠습니다
keep in touch
계속 연락하다
Is there anything else?
다른 것이 있나요?
I will give you an address then
그럼 주소 알려줄게
you come to me
당신은 나에게 와요
looking for you
당신을 찾고
What are you looking for?
무엇을 찾고 계신가요?
I
나
I want to take you away
너를 데려가고 싶어
If it was two years ago
2년 전이었다면
You also said such things to me
너도 나한테 그런 말을 했었지
I will follow you without hesitation
거침없이 따라갈게
Even if it means mountains of swords and seas of fire, I won’t hesitate
칼산, 불바다라도 난 주저하지 않을 거야
But now
그러나 지금
I know
알아요
I mean
내 말은
if you are willing to
당신이 할 의향이 있다면
Why
왜
Why are you showing up again now?
왜 지금 또 나타나나요?
I
나
It took me two full years
꼬박 2년이 걸렸어요
Then I gradually forgot the pain
그러다가 점차 고통을 잊어버렸어요
I finally started my career again
드디어 다시 활동을 시작했어요
my life
내 인생
But now you appear again
그런데 이제 또 나타나네
Let these past events be vividly remembered
과거의 사건을 생생하게 기억하게 해주세요
Why haven't you sailed yet?
왜 아직 항해하지 않았나요?
The river is blocked
강이 막혔어요
After the lockdown is lifted
봉쇄가 해제된 후
let's go
갑시다
You go back to sleep first
너 먼저 다시 자거라
stop
멈추다
I knew it
알고 있었어
that moment
그 순간
Did you read clearly what was on the note?
메모에 적힌 내용을 명확하게 읽었습니까?
who is wild horse
야생마는 누구인가
my superior
내 상사
The telegram said
전보에 따르면
Secret peace talks have been leaked
비밀 평화회담이 유출됐다
The Gendarmerie Command has taken action
헌병대 사령부가 조치를 취했습니다
what's going on
무슨 일이야
Recently, Chongqing has to negotiate with the Japanese government
최근 충칭은 일본 정부와 협상을 해야 한다.
A secret peace talk in Shanghai
상하이에서 비밀 평화회담
It's not the first time
처음이 아니야
What result can be reached?
어떤 결과를 얻을 수 있습니까?
Wild horses let's try to protect the peace negotiators
야생마들아 평화협상가들을 보호하자
Why are we leaving Shanghai?
우리는 왜 상하이를 떠나는 걸까요?
This peace negotiation is not as simple as you think
이번 평화협상은 생각보다 간단하지 않다
If you get stuck in it
그 안에 갇혀버리면
will bring very big consequences
매우 큰 결과를 가져올 것이다
If peace talks can bring the war to an early end
평화회담이 전쟁을 조기에 종식시킬 수 있다면
What's wrong
뭐가 문제 야
you are too naive
당신은 너무 순진해요
If I continue to lurk
계속해서 숨어 있으면
You can definitely complete the task
당신은 확실히 임무를 완료할 수 있습니다
Your mission has been completed
당신의 임무가 완료되었습니다
you are disobeying orders
당신은 명령을 거역하고 있습니다
Order
주문하다
Order is business
주문은 사업이다
Some business can be done
일부 사업은 완료될 수 있습니다.
Some businesses cannot be done
일부 사업은 할 수 없습니다
That's not what you told me
당신이 나한테 한 말은 그게 아니었어요
You say it is your duty to obey orders
당신은 명령에 복종하는 것이 당신의 의무라고 말하죠
I treat you as one of my own
나는 당신을 내 사람으로 대합니다
That’s why I’m telling you this
그게 내가???너한테 말하는 이유야
Refuse to perform tasks
작업 수행을 거부
How do you explain it to your superiors?
상사에게 어떻게 설명하나요?
I will tell them
내가 그들에게 말할 게
around the river
강 주변
There is radio detection vehicle activity
무선 감지 차량 활동이 있습니다
We didn't use the radio
우리는 라디오를 사용하지 않았습니다
I didn't receive the order
주문을 받지 못했습니다
besides
게다가
Received the news
소식을 받았습니다
Said Jiangmyeon will be unblocked tomorrow night
내일 밤에 강면이 차단 해제될 거라고 하더군요
before this
이 전에
Don't even think about leaving the cabin
기내에서 나갈 생각도 하지 마세요
You'd better think about it carefully
잘 생각해보시면 좋을 것 같아요
Facing boss Dai’s reward
보스 다이???의 보상을 마주하다
How to behave well?
어떻게 하면 잘 행동할 수 있나요?
The illustrious military exploits you have made
당신이 이룩한 빛나는 군사적 위업
right there
바로 거기
Has anyone been in there?
거기에 가본 사람이 있나요?
Only the cold dew comes in and out
차가운 이슬만 들어오고 나간다
what is she busy with
그 사람 뭐하느라 바빠?
She bought a lot of things
그녀는 많은 것을 샀다
what
무엇
some tea red wine
차 레드 와인 약간
and some food
그리고 음식 좀
wine
와인
Quite romantic
꽤 로맨틱하다
which kind of food
어떤 음식인지
Listen to Chen Shugan who is following her
그녀를 팔로우하는 Chen Shugan의 말을 들어보세요.
She also bought some ingredients for Chinese and Western food
그녀는 또한 중국 음식과 서양 음식에 필요한 재료도 구입했습니다.
I also went to a Japanese food store specifically
특별히 일본 식품점에도 갔어요
We're following the right place
우리는 올바른 장소를 따라가고 있습니다
It seems that this negotiation will take a long time
이번 협상은 시간이 오래 걸릴 것 같다
Jiang Zhaoguo asked her to come here first to make some preparations.
Jiang Zhaoguo는 그녀에게 먼저 여기로 와서 준비를 하라고 요청했습니다.
that person
저 사람
It should be Jiang Zhaoguo
장자오궈(Jiang Zhaoguo)가 되어야 한다
Then should we take action?
그러면 조치를 취해야 할까요?
Don't alert the snake
뱀에게 경고하지 마세요
Wait for the Japanese representative to come
일본 대표가 올 때까지 기다리세요
Let's do it together
함께 해보자
Han Lu, what is she doing?
한루야, 쟤 뭐하는 거야?
Xiao Wu eats
샤오우가 먹는다
Wait for the boat to leave
보트가 떠날 때까지 기다리세요
Take off her chain
그녀의 사슬을 풀어라
good
좋은
Received another telegram from Ye Ye
Ye Ye로부터 또 다른 전보를 받았습니다
Still asking
아직도 묻는 중
leave them alone
그들을 내버려 둬
What's wrong
뭐가 문제 야
Miss Hanlu
미스 한루
do you know
당신은 알고 있나요
What a stupid thing you did
정말 멍청한 짓을 한 거야?
what did i do
내가 뭘 한거지
Follow you to the man at No. 22, Petain Road
No. 22, Petain Road에 있는 남자를 따라가세요.
It's not Jiang Zhaoguo at all, right?
전혀 Jiang Zhaoguo가 아니죠?
It's the actor you're looking for in the crew
당신이 찾고 있는 제작진의 배우입니다
In your last movie, "Spring Light"
마지막 영화 '스프링 라이트'에서
He plays the bank manager
그는 은행 지점장을 연기한다
You can't protect Jiang Zhaoguo at all by doing this.
이렇게 하면 장자오궈를 전혀 보호할 수 없습니다.
You don't have to worry about my affairs
내 일에 대해 걱정할 필요가 없습니다
It's not a question of whether you care or not
신경쓰고 안쓰고의 문제가 아니야
But if you say this
그런데 이렇게 말하면
It will only put you in more danger
너를 더 위험하게 만들 뿐이야
If Zhao An discovers
조안이 발견하면
You are a puzzle
당신은 퍼즐입니다
Interfering with their vision
시력을 방해함
Then take a seat
그럼 자리에 앉으세요
You are related to Jiang Zhaoguo
당신은 장자오궈(Jiang Zhaoguo)와 관련이 있습니다
Not only are there connections
인연이 있을 뿐만 아니라
Are you still trying to cover up Jiang Zhaoguo?
아직도 장자오궈를 은폐하려고 하시나요?
I told you before
내가 전에 말했잖아
Jiang Zhaoguo is Zhao An’s assassination target
Jiang Zhaoguo는 Zhao An의 암살 대상입니다
and now you
그리고 지금 당신은
Became the one who could find Jiang Zhaoguo
장조궈를 찾을 수 있는 사람이 되었어요
only clue
유일한 단서
So what will Zhao An do?
그렇다면 조안은 무엇을 할 것인가?
So what should I do now
그럼 이제 어떻게 해야 할까요?
Get out of here with me right now
지금 당장 나와 함께 여기서 나가세요
But my new movie hasn’t been finished yet
하지만 내 새 영화는 아직 끝나지 않았어
Filmmaking is full of surprises
영화 제작은 놀라움으로 가득 차 있습니다
There are some that have been filmed but not released yet.
촬영은 되었지만 아직 공개되지 않은 작품도 있습니다.
Say goodbye to your new movie
새 영화에 작별 인사를 하세요
Miss Hanlu
미스 한루
This hotel is run by French people
이 호텔은 프랑스인이 운영하는 호텔입니다.
An invitation is required to enter
입장하려면 초대장이 필요합니다.
you are safe here
넌 여기 안전해
Thank you
감사합니다
You shouldn't thank me
나한테 고마워하면 안 돼
I should thank my friends
친구들에게 감사해야겠어요
Know-it-all about the French Concession
프랑스 조계지에 대한 모든 것을 알고 있습니다.
Naruko
나루코
It's an honor to serve you
당신을 섬길 수 있어서 영광이에요
Thanks
감사해요
Miss Hanlu
미스 한루
Now you can tell me
이제 말해도 돼
About Jiang Zhaoguo’s situation?
Jiang Zhaoguo의 상황에 대해서요?
before him
그 앞에
An official from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Nationalist Government
국민정부 외교부 관계자
Previously in charge of concession affairs
이전에는 양허 업무를 담당했습니다.
So I often come to Shanghai for business
그래서 상하이에 사업차 자주 오는데요
I met him two years ago
나는 그 사람을 2년 전에 만났어요.
But this time he suddenly appeared
그런데 이번에 갑자기 나타나서
I don’t know what it is specifically.
구체적으로 무엇인지는 모르겠습니다.
Just asked me to rent a house for him
방금 나한테 집을 빌려달라고 했어
Do you have his contact information?
그 사람 연락처 알고 있나요?
No
아니요
He was the one who found me
나를 찾아준 사람이 바로 그 사람이었어
Then you have an appointment
그럼 약속이 있잖아
Is it time to meet next time?
다음에 만날 시간인가요?
No
아니요
good
좋은
Miss Hanlu
미스 한루
Have a good rest in the hotel
호텔에서 편히 쉬세요
Someone will bring you food every day
누군가가 매일 음식을 가져다 줄 거예요
Don't open the curtains
커튼을 열지 마세요
Don't leave the hotel even half a step
반걸음이라도 호텔 밖으로 나가지 마세요.
do you understand
이해했나요
good
좋은
goodbye
안녕히 가세요
Is he in danger?
그가 위험에 처해 있나요?
Very dangerous
매우 위험한
can you protect him
당신은 그를 보호할 수 있나요
try your best
최고의 노력을
goodbye
안녕히 가세요
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
Jiaxing
가흥
Several people
여러 사람
three
삼
Show me the freight certificate.
화물 증명서를 보여주세요.
They're all here
다들 여기 있어요
pass
통과하다
Go get a new epidemic prevention certificate
새로운 방역증명서를 받으러 가세요
I didn’t say I needed to prepare the epidemic prevention certificate before.
예전에는 방역증명서를 준비해야 한다고는 말하지 않았습니다.
There has been an epidemic of dysentery in Shanghai recently
최근 상하이에 이질이 유행했습니다.
An epidemic prevention certificate is required to enter and exit the pier
부두에 출입하려면 전염병 예방 증명서가 필요합니다.
If nothing can be done, go to the Shiliupu Wharf Clinic.
아무것도 할 수 없다면 Shiliupu 부두 클리닉으로 가십시오.
take inspection
검사를 받다
Then reissue
그런 다음 재발행
Okay, I'll go right now
알았어, 지금 바로 갈게
All three of you have to go
셋 다 가야 해
Master, this is me
선생님, 저예요
Someone inside has a fever
안에 누군가 열이 나네요
Another person takes care of her
다른 사람이 그녀를 돌본다
How about you
당신은 어떤가요
Can't I go by myself?
나 혼자 가면 안 돼?
That won't work
작동하지 않습니다
Look at that
저것 봐
Sorry for causing trouble
물의를 일으켜 죄송합니다
Okay, hurry up
알았어, 서둘러
Once the certificate is obtained, the ship will be dispatched.
인증서를 취득하면 선박이 발송됩니다.
OK
좋아요
two days later
이틀 후
It's still this time
아직 이 시간이야
I will contact you again
다시 연락드리겠습니다